# Christopher Glinka

# Jr. Software Developer & Systems Analyst

#### Contact

Edmonton, AB (587) 778 8210 glinkachris@gmail.com

#### **Profiles**

Portfolio: <u>cglinkadesigns.com</u> LinkedIn: Christopher Glinka

GitHub: CGlinka95

# **Key Skills**

Communication Team Leadership Mentoring **Project Management JavaScript** React MUI C# .Net Core SQL Transactional SQL Java HTML CSS Bootstrap Flutter/Dart.js

Node.js

Linq Python

#### **Summary**

An aspiring and enthusiastic Software Developer with 3 years of technical education in NAIT's DMIT program. A graduate of Concordia University of Edmonton with a major in English and a minor in Psychology but decided that IT is ultimately where he belongs and flourishes due to a life-long interest and fascination with technology. Has recently, due to his work at Code Ninjas, discovered a passion for teaching kids how to code and make their own videogames; while also giving back to the community in ways that motivate and foster the same passion for technology and STEM that he feels.

### **Experience**

React Web Portfolio • cglinkadesigns.com

Worked on and completed a custom website that showcases the knowledge and ability required for making creative and intuitive designs.

- Technologies used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, and EmailJS
- The whole project is accessible across many devices and is deployed by me and hosted under my own domain through hostinger.com.
- This project was fun to work on and taught me more about state (the navigation bar), APIs such as EmailJS, and deployment.
- Other projects that I am most proud of can also be accessed and viewed through the website.

October 2021 - Present

Director of Education • Code Ninjas, St. Albert & Windermere Teaching children ages 6-15 about coding concepts based on an evolving curriculum, starting with block coding, transitioning to JavaScript and eventually Lua, C#, and Unity game engine.

- Assisted on the Code Ninjas Windermere team that was recently awarded the Black Belt Center 2022 award for being in the top 5% of the company.
- Leadership role on the Code Ninjas, St. Albert team that broke more company-wide records for a single location's grand opening. 70+ student sign-ups prior to opening day, then breaking-even and surpassing 120 active accounts within 3 months of operation.

- Successfully constructed and taught multiple curriculums for various summer camps, including Web Development, beginner and intermediate Roblox Studio development, Lego robotics, and 3D modelling and printing.
- Awarded the St. Albert center's 'Got Yo' Back' award for always going above and beyond my direct responsibilities, being willing to lend a helping hand, having consistent reliability, and attending additional events and fundraisers, such as Autism Edmonton, to help the company grow and give back to the community.

July 2021 – November 2021 Barista • Starbucks, Namao, Edmonton

January 2014 – March 2020 Senior Sales Associate & Key-holder • GameStop, St. Albert

#### Education

September 2020 – Present

DMIT • Northern Alberta Institute of Technology

Studying in the Computer Software Development stream.

- Dean's Honor Roll 2021 & 2022
- Worked on a team of 3 other software developers to create a mock web application for a motorcycle shop's backend system from the ground up.
  - Technologies used: C#, .NET Core 6.0, Entity Framework, T-SQL, HTML, and holiday.css.
  - Each member was given their own department of the application to work on and complete: Purchasing, Receiving, Servicing, and Sales.
  - My task was to build the frontend UI/UX and backend business logic and data processing/transferal for the Servicing system.
  - The project can be viewed on my GitHub profile under eBike-WebApp.

September 2016 – April 2020

Bachelor of Arts • Concordia University of Edmonton

Graduated with a Major in English and a Minor in Psychology.

 Excelled in group research projects that present data and important information in an accessible and concise manner, both written and presentation format.

# References

Dan Mouris • NAIT Instructor

Email: <u>dmouris@nait.ca</u>

Shannon Stevenson • Director of Operations and Owner of Code

Ninjas St. Albert & Windermere

Phone: (825) 440 5485

Email: <a href="mailto:shannon.stevenson@codeninjas.com">shannon.stevenson@codeninjas.com</a>

Annabelle Syms • Director of Customer Service at Code Ninjas

Windermere

Phone: (780) 236 1536

Email: annabelle.syms@gmail.com

Ryan Stevenson • Ent. & Bus Applications Specialist at NTT Data

Phone: (825) 440 5480

Email: <a href="mailto:rbstevenson@hotmail.com">rbstevenson@hotmail.com</a>